ODINAKA JOY



dinakajoy@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/dinakaiov



dinakaiov.com



PROFILE

A Software Engineer with +3 years of professional experience, +3 years of JavaScript experience and ~1 year of functional programming experience using OCaml. Experience working on full-stack web environments, in a fast-paced, SaaS start-up environment and also in open-source. Able to take a project from design to product, using the best tools and architectures based on the application needs. Basic knowledge of project and people management, having led the completion of two projects (an ERP and an e-learning system) from start to finish. Passionate about coding, open source and education. Confident, curious and adaptable.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer @ AcceleratorApp || February 2022 - Present

- AcceleratorApp is a startup management application that incubators use to request applications from startups, manage and track the process, and assign and monitor mentors, staff and coaches. Users have different roles such as Admin, Admin&Coach, Sub-Admin, Coach, Staff, Mentors, Startup Co/Founders, and Applicants.
- Continuously build, test and deploy daily.
- Daily tasks include fixing bugs, updating existing features and implementing new features.
- => Skills: CSS, SCSS, TypeScript, React.js, Gatsby.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, GraphQL API, Kafka, Redis, Docker, Elastic Search, etc.

Web Developer @ Metrova Technologies | December 2019 – January 2022

- Led the completion of over 15 full-stack applications for clients
- Rebuilt some projects formerly designed with WordPress, as single-page applications which increased performance by 400%, accessibility by 20% and security by 200%
- Developed features and improvements to products in a modern, maintainable, secure, well-tested, and performant way
- Worked with Product Management and other stakeholders to iterate on new features within the product
- Crafted code that meets our internal standards for style, maintainability, and best practices for a high-scale web environment, and maintained and advocated for these standards through code review
- Consistently shipped small features and improvements with minimal guidance and support from other team members
- => Skills: CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, REST API, GraphQL API

Web Development @ Google Africa Developers Program || May 2019 - February 2020

- Certified as a Mobile Web Specialist
- Specialized in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Completed the following projects during the course of the program https://github.com/dinakajoy/pixel-art-maker-app, https://github.com/dinakajov/Credit Card Validation, https://github.com/dinakajov/api_teamwork, https://github.com/dinakajoy/mini-netflix-movie-app, https://github.com/dinakajoy/mini-netflix-api

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

Tarides-UK || January 2022 - July 2022

- Added functionality for Irmin (a primarily Unix-based application) to work in the browser using WebSocket
- Combined Irmin-Indexeddb and Irmin-Server to produce an offline-first web application with fast and efficient synchronization.
- Combined Dream's GraphQL and Irmin-GraphQL to build a mini-github application that fetches and displays a GitHub repository's information such as name, author, description and README.md file

More Details => https://tarides.com/blog/2022-08-02-irmin-in-the-browser

Loctech IT Solutions | September 2021 - December 2021

 Led two other developers to build the company website with an eLearning system integrated into it, as a JAMStack application using Gatsby.js and StrapiCMS.

Link => Loctech Website

OCaml Community - Outreachy Intern || May 2021 - August 2021

• Designed a GraphQL API to access all OCaml packages with features like sorting, searching, filtering and pagination, making it easier to query all the packages.

Link => https://github.com/ocaml/v3.ocaml.org-server/pull/78, https://ocaml.org/graphiql

Loctech IT Solutions || August 2020 - December 2020

- Led the completion of an ERP application using React.js, Material-UI, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB and PostgreSQL
- Worked with four other developers as the team lead/project manager Link => <u>KingsooERP</u>

EDUCATION

Federal Polytechnic Nekede Owerri | 2011 - 2016

• Higher National Diploma in Computer Science